corank.com 2013-07-24

# coRank > Terms of Service > Privacy Policy

We, the people behind **coRank** , also use the Internet on a daily basis...a lot! And just like you, we care about our own privacy when we surf the Internet. That is why our privacy policy was conceived so that all **coRank** users can have the utmost confidence that their information,be it public or private, is treated the same way we would like ours to be treated. 

Please read the following information to understand our commitment to the privacy of each and every **coRank** user. 

## Who has access to your data?

When you sign up with **coRank** , the only information we request from you is a username, your email address and a password. 

Out of those three pieces of information, only your username will be visible to others. 

Further, you can complete your profile by entering additional information. The only other information from your profile that becomes available to others - assuming you entered it - is your name, last name, your country and region or state, your blog, your photo or avatar and your "about me" description. 

Also, as you post new stories or comments to a story, the content associated to that submission is considered to be placed in the public domain unless you specifically say so at the time of posting it. 

Except in some specific circumstances - mentioned later - absolutely nobody has access to any other information you enter when you sign up with **coRank** , with the exception of yourself and a restricted group of **coRank** employees should they need such access for support or maintenance reasons or to get in direct contact with you. 

Later, as you start using coRank, some statistics also become available to others, such as how many stories you have submitted, how many votes you've made (both positive and negative), how many people are your sources, for how many people you are a source, and how many people have visited your profile page. 

## Can coRank disclose your information to third parties?

**coRank** will not sell, publish or deliver to third parties any of the private information entered by **coRank** users under any circumstance, except when we are required for legal reasons. 

We might have to deliver personal information to a third party in order to protect our intellectual property, in any case always abiding to legal obligations. 

**Child Pornography:**  
Should **coRank** find any child pornography content of any kind posted by you on your account, **coRank** will immediately notify the corresponding authorities, law enforcement agencies and the FBI, making available to them all information related to this activity, including but not limited to IP addresses and timestamps. 

The use of **coRank** implies the acceptance of this clause. If you do not wish **coRank** to share your information and use of the service with the corresponding authorities, law enforcement agencies and the FBI, do not engage on these "activities", period. 

Accidental running into any of the content described above does **not** result in reporting your account activities to the authorities, and is protected by our general privacy policy. 

## What information is exposed when I post a comment?

Your comment will be associated to your user name, and posted in its entirety - except for certain HTML tags that are automatically filtered out - and available for anyone to see. 

Comments, once posted, cannot be modified or deleted. Do not include in your comments any information you wish to keep private. 

## Does coRank have any interest in my personal information?

**coRank** may use several parameters to quantify certain general statistics, such as the number of visits to a particular story, topics more visited by a particular user, etc. 

**coRank** will only use this information to better serve targeted advertising, but will never make any of this information available to third parties. 

**coRank** also produces and keeps for a limited period of time a history log of your access to the services offered by **coRank** , including web page access, posted comments, votes, and other information regarding your access to our services, such as date and time, IP from where you connect, account you sign in and actions performed on the site, with the sole purpose of having a mechanism that allows us to investigate service abuse or to provide better technical assistance whenever is required, for example when you contact our technical support team. 

**coRank** is committed to not use this information for commercial reasons of any kind, except in the cases just explained above. 

## Will coRank use my email address to send me unsolicited emails?

NOT EVER! **coRank** will never use your email address to send you unsolicited email. 

Any message originated in our servers that you may feel was _unsolicited_ is always the result of the actions of another **coRank** user - for example when a user decides to add you as a source, you will usually receive an email from **coRank** asking for your acceptance or rejection. 

Sometimes we may also feel that we have to send a message to several or all registered users because we believe it is **absolutely necessary** to do so, and always responding to administrative reasons. 

It is also possible that sometimes an **coRank** team member might contact you personally for some specific reason. 

## What legal guarantee does coRank offers regarding the privacy of my data?

**coRank** takes very seriously the privacy of our users and clients, as well as the privacy and security of our systems; we follow these things very closely, use industry standard measures to protect our system and have a 24/7 monitoring team. However, and although we have never had any security breach ever since we are in business, we cannot guarantee that nobody would ever break into our systems in the future. Also, much of the information that travels between your machine and ours, does it so in "plain text", that is, it does not travel encrypted, and so it is vulnerable from eavesdropping attacks. 

For these reasons, **coRank** cannot be and is not responsible of any event that results in someone other than **coRank** or yourself from obtaining any information stored in our servers. 

## What should I do if I think my account has been compromised?

Send us immediately a message through the forms you can find in http://www.coRank.com/contact.html, indicating in the subject "SECURITY PROBLEM". Your message will be processed, depending on the seriousness of the problem, either immediately or within 24-48 hours. 

Normally, when this happens, it is because your email address has been compromised before anyone can gain access to your account in **coRank** , so it is a wise thing to do to use a different email address in the meantime. 

Remember, your account at **coRank** is only as safe as your email address. If someone gains access to your mailbox, they may also gain access to your account at **coRank**. 

## coRank uses _cookies_. Could this pose a security concern?

In more than seven years that we've been offering Internet services, the use of cookies has never resulted in a security problem. **coRank** requires that you have cookies activated so that you can easily navigate through our pages. The cookies used by **coRank** do not study your habits nor are used for any other obscure reason, simply, they help us to know who you are so that you don't have to keep signing in. 

## Should coRank use advertising agencies, how will these agencies use my personal information?

**coRank** may work with one or several advertising agencies to provide advertising in our web pages or RSS feeds. However, **coRank** will never release any of your private or confidential information to any of these companies for any reason. 

## Data acquisition and cancellation

**coRank** enforces a policy of zero tolerance regarding fraudulent data acquisition or submission. Not only **coRank** condemns such practices, but will also work with the law enforcement whenever we consider that our services have been used by obtaining or submitting fraudulent information. 

Personal data information will be cancelled whenever it is no longer needed for the purpose of which it was obtained in the first place. Such data will not be kept in our files in such ways that might be used to identify a particular individual for a period longer than what was needed for the purpose of which it was obtained. 

## Modifications and Revisions

This Privacy Policy will be reviewed periodically to make sure that it serves the needs of **coRank** as well as our clients and users and the current legislature. We we will always try to let our clients and users know about any changes to this policy in advance, either by updating this page, sending a message to all affected users, or by posting a prominent note in our main home page or blog. However, we do not guarantee that such notice, in advance or not, will take place. In order to keep yourself updated with this policy, we suggest you visit this page periodically. 

Should you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please contact us by visiting [_http://www.coRank.com/contact-legal.html_](http://www.corank.com/contact-legal.html).
